punchbowl.com 2019-05-07

# Punchbowl.com

**This policy is effective as of May 25, 2018.**

Punchbowl, Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy and providing you the most powerful and safe online experience. This publication intends to help you understand how personal information you provide to Punchbowl, Inc. is collected and used, so you can make informed decisions when using the website located at https://www.punchbowl.com ("Punchbowl"). 

By using Punchbowl, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. Notices of all changes that materially affect ways that your personally identifiable information may be used or shared will be posted in updates to our privacy policy. If you continue to use Punchbowl and services after these notices of changes have been posted to the site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices. 

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact: [privacy@punchbowl.com](mailto:privacy@punchbowl.com). 

##  Personal Information We Collect 

In order to become a Punchbowl member you must first register for our service. During this registration process you are required to provide personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address and name. Once you are a member you may provide additional information for your member profile such as home address, zip code, date of birth, gender, preferences, interests and favorites. Providing additional information beyond what is required at registration is optional, but will allow you to better identify yourself and find services at Punchbowl. 

Punchbowl, Inc. does not solicit, or knowingly collect and store personal information from anyone under the age of 13. Punchbowl, Inc. will immediately remove and delete any and all information from anyone under 13 if notification is provided that a person under 13 registered at Punchbowl. If you have a reason to believe information was collected about a child under 13, please contact [privacy@punchbowl.com](mailto:privacy@punchbowl.com). 

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Punchbowl, Inc. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, pages visited, features used and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by Punchbowl, Inc. for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of Punchbowl. 

In order to invite others to view your Punchbowl page, you must provide Punchbowl, Inc. with their email addresses or phone number. In order to send messages to your guests through Punchbowl, we require that you submit to Punchbowl current, valid email addresses or phone numbers for your guests. When you send messages to your guests, we collect and retain the email addresses, phone number, or other pertinent contact information of those persons to whom you send the message. Even though we retain contact information about your guests, Punchbowl, Inc. will not use these email addresses to send promotional communications, newsletters, or service announcements without your explicit permission, nor will we intentionally sell or otherwise disclose guest contact information that you submit to any third party. If a guest chooses to register with Punchbowl, that individual will be considered a Punchbowl member and may receive promotional communications, newsletters, and service announcements from Punchbowl, Inc. according to the terms and conditions of this privacy policy. 

If you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Punchbowl public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Punchbowl, Inc. does not read any of your private online communications. 

Punchbowl, Inc. encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from Punchbowl so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. Punchbowl, Inc. is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the Punchbowl and Punchbowl, Inc. family of Web sites. 

##  How We Use Your Personal Information 

Punchbowl, Inc. collects and uses your personal information to operate Punchbowl and deliver the services you have requested. When you register with Punchbowl, you are automatically enrolled in our marketing emails. These marketing emails have information about upcoming holidays, new features, and useful tips about using the website. If you do not wish to receive these marketing emails, simply unsubscribe the first time you receive an email. You can quickly and easily unsubscribe by clicking the "Unsubscribe" links in the email. When you unsubscribe, you will no longer receive the marketing emails. However, you will continue to receive emails that are related to your usage of the Punchbowl website. Punchbowl, Inc. also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Punchbowl, Inc. and its affiliates. Punchbowl, Inc. may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. Punchbowl, Inc. will communicate with you through emails and messages posted on Punchbowl. 

Punchbowl, Inc. may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of carefully selected business partners about a particular offering that we believe may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, zip code) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Punchbowl, Inc. may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Punchbowl, Inc., and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. 

From time to time, Punchbowl, Inc. may enter into strategic partnerships in which your personally identifiable information may be provided to a carefully selected business partner. These strategic partnerships may include private-label, co-branded websites, or other promotional web pages for which Punchbowl, Inc. receives financial compensation. Any strategic partners to whom we disclose personal information may have their own privacy policies, which describe how they use and disclose personal information. Those policies will govern use, handling and disclosure of your personal information once we have shared it with those strategic partners as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Punchbowl, Inc. keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within Punchbowl, in order to determine what Punchbowl, Inc. services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Punchbowl to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area. 

Punchbowl, Inc. will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Punchbowl, Inc. or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Punchbowl, Inc.; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Punchbowl, Inc., or the public. 

Notwithstanding any other provision, we may allow third parties to monitor Site activity using cookies, web beacons and similar technologies for the purpose of reporting website traffic, statistics, targeted advertisements, “click-throughs” and/or other activities. We may also engage a data provider who may collect web log data from you (including IP address and information about your browser or operating system) through cookies. The cookies may reflect demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, that we may share with a data provider solely in hashed, non-human readable form. Our partners may place or recognize a cookie on your computer or device via their pixel on our website and in email communications you've opted to receive from us. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms over time for advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes. This information is used to help select and display targeted advertisements that are believed to be of interest to you (sometimes called "online behavioral advertising" or "interest-based advertising" or "OBA"). If you would like to "opt-out" of being served OBA on the Website by our third-party advertising companies, please go to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. 

Notwithstanding anything else in this policy, we or a data partner we have engaged may collect and store a unique identifier matched to your mobile device, in order to deliver customized ads or content while you use applications or surf the internet, or to seek to identify you in a unique manner across other devices or browsers. In order to customize these ads or content, we or a data partner may connect de-identified demographic or other data about you (received from third parties) either to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, or to data passively collected from you, such as your device identifier or IP address. To learn about how to opt-out, please go to <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. 

##  Use of Cookies 

Like most websites, Punchbowl, Inc. uses "cookies" to allow you to bypass the login screen ("Remember Me" functionality). A cookie is a tiny data file, which resides on your computer and allows Punchbowl, Inc. to recognize you as a member when you return to Punchbowl from the same computer and browser. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, when you register with Punchbowl, a cookie helps Punchbowl, Inc. to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to Punchbowl, the information you previously provided can be retrieved. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the features of the Punchbowl services. 

##  Security of Your Personal Information 

Punchbowl, Inc. secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Punchbowl, Inc. secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

##  How You Can Control Your Personal Information 

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways: 

If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at [privacy@punchbowl.com](mailto:privacy@punchbowl.com). 

If you wish to unsubscribe from receiving marketing emails from Punchbowl, Inc. please click the unsubscribe link included in the footer of all of our emails. 

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please email at [privacy@punchbowl.com](mailto:privacy@punchbowl.com). We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect. You may also request that we delete the information we have collected about you at any time by emailing us at [privacy@punchbowl.com](mailto:privacy@punchbowl.com). Please note that in certain circumstances, we may not be able to completely remove your information from our systems. For example, we may retain your information for legitimate business purposes, if it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, for account recovery purposes, if required by law or as retained in our data backup systems or cached or archived pages, or where the burden or expense of accommodating your request would, in our good faith judgment, be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy, or where the rights of others may be violated. All retained personal information will continue to be subject to the terms of the Privacy Policy to which the User has previously agreed. 

Finally, you may request access to the information we have collected about you by sending a request to [privacy@punchbowl.com](mailto:privacy@punchbowl.com). 

##  International Users 

This Privacy Policy applies when you are using our Services globally. If you are using our Services from a country outside the United States, you acknowledge and agree that your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States, and is subject to the laws of the United States. You acknowledge that the United States may have data protection laws less stringent than or otherwise different from the laws in effect in the country in which you are located. Where we transfer your personal information out of the country in which you are located, we will take steps to ensure that your personal information receives an adequate level of protection where it is processed and your rights continue to be protected. 

##  Changes to this Privacy Policy 

Punchbowl, Inc. will occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we make changes, we will post the updated Privacy Policy here and will revise the effective date at the top of this agreement. We recommend that you check our website from time to time to inform yourself of any changes to the Privacy Policy. 

##  Contact Information 

Punchbowl, Inc. welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you believe that Punchbowl, Inc. has not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please contact Punchbowl, Inc. at [privacy@punchbowl.com](mailto:privacy@punchbowl.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
